A Guide to the Papers of Ruth G. Hale 1970-2001
Roanoke Public Libraries
- Craig County Records and Families (Box 17)
  - Birth, Marriages and Obituaries undated (Folder 16)
  - Caldwell Family Cemetery undated (Folder 17)
  - Crawford Family Cemetery undated (Folder 18)
  - Givens, Hypes and Paitsel Family Cemeteries undated (Folder 19)
  - Huffman Family Cemetery undated (Folder 20)
  - Hutchinson Family Cemetery undated (Folder 21)
  - Kent Family Cemetery undated (Folder 22)
  - Level Green Cemetery undated (Folder 23)
  - McGuire and Jones Family Cemeteries undated (Folder 24)
  - Rowan Family Cemetery undated (Folder 25)
  - Ross Family Cemetery undated (Folder 26)
  - Williams Family Cemetery undated (Folder 27)
- Craig County Records and Families (Box 18)
  - Census Records 1900 (Folder 1)
  - Census Records 1920 (Folder 2)
  - Deaths undated (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Records undated (Folder 4)
  - Smith Family undated (Folder 5)
  - Census Records undated (Folder 6)
- Cemetery Records and County Histories (Box 19)
  - Virginia and West Virginia Counties - Craig, Botetourt, Giles, Roanoke, Rockingham, Mercer, Monroe, Roane and Summers undated (Folder 1)
  - Roanoke County - Catawba Cemetery undated (Folder 2)
  - Roanoke County - Masons Cove Cemetery undated (Folder 3)
  - Roanoke County - Cemeteries on the line with Montgomery County undated (Folder 4)
  - Roanoke County - Martins Creek Cemetery undated (Folder 5)
  - Salem Cemeteries undated (Folder 6)
  - Roanoke County - Mountain View, Grisso Family, Halls Family, Hall Family, Brillhart Family and Crossroads Cemeteries undated (Folder 7)
  - Roanoke County - Route 220 South Cemeteries undated (Folder 8)
  - Roanoke County - Burkett Family, Mangus-Mountcastle Family, Riley Family, Gearhart Family, Oliver Family, Buzzard Rock, Butt Family, Smith Family, Mountain View, Small Family, Blueridge Memorial Gardens, Crawford Family, Hall Family and Moores Chapel Cemeteries undated (Folder 9)
  - County Histories - Bedford undated (Folder 10)
  - County Histories - Botetourt undated (Folder 11)
  - County Histories - Carroll undated (Folder 12)
  - County Histories - Dickenson undated (Folder 13)
  - County Histories - Franklin undated (Folder 14)
  - County Histories - Fluvanna undated (Folder 15)
  - County Histories - Grayson undated (Folder 16)
  - County Histories - Louisa undated (Folder 17)
  - County Histories - Montgomery undated (Folder 18)
  - County Histories - Patrick undated (Folder 19)
  - County Histories - Pittsylvania undated (Folder 20)
  - County Histories - Pulaski undated (Folder 21)
  - County Histories - Russell undated (Folder 22)
  - County Histories - Scott undated (Folder 23)
  - County Histories - Smyth undated (Folder 24)
  - County Histories - Tazewell undated (Folder 25)
  - County Histories - Wythe undated (Folder 26)
  - Virginia County Formations undated (Folder 27)
  - Virginia and West Virginia Counties - Bedford, Carroll, Craig, Floyd, Franklin, Frederick, Montgomery, Page, Roanoke, Rockingham, Shenandoah, York and Mercer Counties undated (Folder 28)
- Family Group Sheets, Correspondence and Various Family Records (Box 20)
  - Family Group Sheets - Davis, Garman, Brillhart, Martin, Bradford, Vaden and Graham undated (Folder 1)
  - Family Group Sheets - Bradford undated (Folder 2)
  - Family Group Sheets - Vaden undated (Folder 3)
  - Family Group Sheets - Blankenship undated (Folder 4)
  - Family Group Sheets - Graham undated (Folder 5)
  - Family Group Sheets - Basham undated (Folder 6)
  - Family Group Sheets - Reese undated (Folder 7)
  - Family Group Sheets - Davis undated (Folder 8)
  - Family Group Sheets - Croy, Martin, Hall, VanOver, Sheilds, Bradford and Bain undated (Folder 9)
  - Hale Family Correspondence 1854-1925 (Folder 10)
  - Alls Family Homes undated (Folder 11)
  - Alls Family Photographs and Homes undated (Folder 12)
  - Hall, Garman and Wright Families - Deaths, Marriages, Military Information and Photographs undated (Folder 13)
  - Hall, Garman, and Wright Families - Articles, Deaths, Marriages, Photographs and Surveys undated (Folder 14)
- Craig and Montgomery Counties, Records and Families (Box 21)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries undated (Folder 1)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Den Hill, Dudley Family, Earhart Family, East Hill, Galilee, Gearheart Family, Jennelle Family, Lafayette Family, Madison Family, Mills Family, North Fork, Pepper and Reesedale Family undated (Folder 2)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Richardson Family, Ryan Family, Sessler Family, Sowder Family, Garlic Family, Barnett Family, Correll Family, Lafayette Family, Howard Family, Page Family, Sublett Family, Pepper Family, Turner Family, Wade Family, Vaden Family and Walthall Family undated (Folder 3)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries undated (Folder 4)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries undated (Folder 5)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Christiansburg undated (Folder 6)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Elliston undated (Folder 7)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Riner and Auburn undated (Folder 8)
  - Craig County - Marriages undated (Folder 9)
  - Craig County - Deaths undated (Folder 10)
  - Craig County Cemeteries undated (Folder 11)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Paint Bank undated (Folder 12)
- Cemetery Records (Box 22)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Bell Family, Mill Creek, Caldwell Family, Craig Healing Springs, Hardwick Family, Hutchison Family, Huffman Family, McCartney Family, Snodgrass Family, Thornrose Family, Crawford Family and Memorial-Red Brush undated (Folder 1)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Barbours Creek and Red Brush undated (Folder 2)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Craigs Creek undated (Folder 3)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Abbott Area undated (Folder 4)
  - Craig, Botetourt and Pulaski County Cemeteries undated (Folder 5)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries undated (Folder 6)
  - Franklin County Cemeteries undated (Folder 7)
  - Pulaski County Cemeteries undated (Folder 8)
  - Roanoke County Cemeteries undated (Folder 9)
  - Craig County Cemeteries undated (Folder 10)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Barbours Creek undated (Folder 11)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Johns Creek undated (Folder 12)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - New Castle undated (Folder 13)
  - Craig County Cemeteries - Upper Craig Creek undated (Folder 14)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries undated (Folder 15)
  - Monroe County Cemeteries undated (Folder 16)
- Floyd and Montgomery County Cemetery Records and Frederick County Miscellaneous Records (Box 23)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries - Laurel Creek, Martin Family and Cole Family undated (Folder 1)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries - Along the Blue Ridge Parkway undated (Folder 2)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries - Along Route 8 undated (Folder 3)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries - Along Route 221 undated (Folder 4)
  - Floyd County Cemeteries - Along Pulaski County Border undated (Folder 5)
  - Frederick County Records - Births, Deeds, Grants, Indentures, Marriages and Wills undated (Folder 6)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Ironto and Halls Church undated (Folder 7)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Toms Creek undated (Folder 8)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - Alls Family, Old Hale, Price Family, Dowdy Family, Keister Family, Hardwick Family and Hale-Buck Family undated (Folder 9)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries - West View, Bishop Family, Hall Family, Harvey Family, Long Family, MacDonald Family, Plunkett Family, Robison Family, Shelburne Family, Sibold-Linkous Family, Slusser Family undated (Folder 10)
  - Montgoemry County Cemeteries - Routes 621 and 624 undated (Folder 11)
  - Montgomery County Cemeteries undated (Folder 12)
- Landmarks, Notable Residents and Records of Various Counties (Box 24)
  - Craig and Botetourt Counties - Historic Landmarks, Notable Residents and Marriages undated (Folder 1)
  - Craig, Botetourt and Roanoke Counties - Historic Landmarks, Military Inductees and Marriages undated (Folder 2)
  - Craig, Botetourt, Floyd, Patrick, Carroll, Frederick, Giles, Montgomery, Roanoke and Monroe Counties - Historic Landmarks, Notable Citizens and Military History undated (Folder 3)
  - Montgomery County - Alleghany Districts Deaths undated (Folder 4)
  - Monroe County - Cemeteries, Deaths, Marriages, Notable Residents and Veterans undated (Folder 5)
  - Montgomery and Floyd Counties - Cemeteries, Census Records and Deaths undated (Folder 6)
  - Montgomery, Roanoke and Floyd Counties - Cemeteries and Deaths undated (Folder 7)
  - Montgomery and Giles Counties - Price Family Census Records, Deaths, and Marriages 1850-1910 (Folder 8)
  - Montgomery County - Births, Cemeteries, Census Records, Deaths, Marriages and Smith Family 1830-1910 (Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Records (Box 25)
  - Montgomery County Families - Vaden, Earhart, Crawford and Hardwick undated (Folder 1)
  - Photographs - All, Caldwell, Hale, Abbott, Hughes, Huffman and Bell Families undated (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs undated (Folder 3)
  - Obituaries - Hale, Layman, Brickey, Price, Hall and Alls undated (Folder 4)
  - Craig County Confederate Veterans - History, Rolls, Tax Lists and Cemeteries undated (Folder 5)
  - Obituaries - Christiansburg 1930-1970 (Folder 6)
  - Families Researched at the National Archives - Hale, Broce, Shepherd, Slusser, Anderson, Brickey, All, Buck, McKinzie, Stanifer and Brand undated (Folder 7)
  - Obituaries - Radford News Journal, Montgomery News Messenger and New Castle Record 1880-1940 (Folder 8)
  - Sullivan County Tennessee Marriages 1860-1930 (Folder 9)
  - West Virginia Marriages and Deaths undated (Folder 10)
  - News Clippings on Local History - Craig, Botetourt, Roanoke and Montgomery Counties undated (Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Research on Huffman, Martin, Richardson, Lafon, Eakin, Turner and Calhoun Families undated (Folder 12)
  - Virginia Migrations - Virginia Genealogical Society Conference 1996 (Folder 13)
  - Hale, Ruth - Personal Interests undated (Folder 14)
  - Churches - Catawba, Shiloh, Circuit United Methodist, New Castle, Mount View Christian, Mount Tabor and Slusser 1830-1910 (Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous Records and Research (Box 26)
  - Virginia State Archives Research - Wills, Land Records, Tax Records, Marriages and Births undated (Folder 1)
  - Blue Ridge Rifles undated (Folder 2)
  - Historic Buildings in New Bern, Virginia undated (Folder 3)
  - Computer Research undated (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Glenna Garner undated (Folder 5)
  - Postcards - Paris and London undated (Folder 6)
  - Hale, Ruth - Personal Information undated (Folder 7)
  - Hale, Ruth - Research Methods undated (Folder 8)
  - Military History - Appomattox, Fredericksburg and Spotsylvania undated (Folder 9)
  - Maps - Virginia Counties and Maryland undated (Folder 10)
  - Cemeteries - Bedford, Botetourt, Craig, Montgomery and Roanoke Counties undated (Folder 11)
  - Immigration Records - Ships and Names undated (Folder 12)
  - Census Records - Various Families and Years for Catawba, Botetourt and Tazewell Counties (Folder 13)
  - Photographs - Unidentified undated (Folder 14)
  - Negatives - Unidentified 1981-1998 (Folder 15)
  - Rolodex undated (Folder 16)
  - Hale, Ruth - Biography and Obituary undated (Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous Records and Indexes (Box 27)
  - Marriage Notices and Obituaries undated (Folder 1)
  - Census Records for Various Virginia Counties 1810-1880 (Folder 2)
  - Research Methods Using State Records undated (Folder 3)
  - Contacts - Marriages, Wills and Other Records undated (Folder 4)
  - Research Notes - Waggener, Waggoner, Farley, Graham, Bradford, Blankenship, Francisco, Dallas, Hall and Davis Families undated (Folder 5)
  - Cemeteries - Montgomery and Roanoke Counties undated (Folder 6)
  - Cemeteries - Published in Virginia Appalachian Notes 1977-1989 (Folder 7)
  - Indexes - Marriage and Land Records from Virginia Counties undated (Folder 8)
  - Indexes - Death and Marriage Records from Bedford County undated (Folder 9)
  - Indexes - Marriage Records from Botetourt County undated (Folder 10)
  - Indexes - Land, Death and Marriage Records from Floyd and Franklin Counties undated (Folder 11)
  - Indexes - Birth and Marriage Records from Roanoke City and County undated (Folder 12)
  - Indexes - Birth and Marriage Records from Montgomery County undated (Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Records (Box 28)
  - Records of Esther Ham - Reese and Bess Families undated (Folder 1)
  - Records of Esther Ham - Bess and Graham Families undated (Folder 2)
  - Marriage and Death Records - Hale, Ahl, Alls, Remine, Romine, Broce, Garman, Anderson and Brickey Families undated (Folder 3)
  - Keister Family undated (Folder 4)
  - Greenway Family undated (Folder 5)
  - Hale Family - Captain Edward Hale and Descendants undated (Folder 6)
  - Graham Family undated (Folder 7)
  - Obituaries undated (Folder 8)
  - Tax Lists - Giles County Personal Property 1810 and 1815 (Folder 9)
  - Tax Lists - Tazewell County Personal Property 1830 (Folder 10)
  - Tax Lists - Craig and Montgomery Counties Personal Property 1787-1851 (Folder 11)
  - Tax Lists - Rockingham County Personal Property 1782-1810 (Folder 12)
  - Tax Lists - Augusta, Botetourt, Montgomery and Rockingham Counties various years (Folder 13)
  - Photographs - Hall, Anderson and Walker Families undated (Folder 14)
  - Marriages, Correspondence, Deeds, Wills and Deaths - All, Hall, Hale, Broce, Layman, Pike and Remines undated (Folder 15)
  - Research Notes - Bradford, Blankenship, Martin, Davis and Reese Families undated (Folder 16)
  - Publications - Virginia Genealogical Society undated (Folder 17)
  - Working Pedigrees - Vanover, Buys, Adriaenzen, Graham, Adkins, Martin, Francisco, Blankenship and Hall Families undated (Folder 18)
- Miscellaneous Records (Box 29)
  - Records - Lotz Funeral Home undated (Folder 1)
  - Marriages - Virginia Counties undated (Folder 2)
  - Records - Rader Funeral Home, Troutville undated (Folder 3)
  - Records - Oakeys Funeral Home, Roanoke and Salem undated (Folder 4)
  - Records - Oakeys Funeral Home undated (Folder 5)
  - Draper Manuscripts - Excerpts on Price and Ledgerwood Families undated (Folder 6)
  - Photographs - Gardner and McDonald Families undated (Folder 7)
  - Photographs - Hale, Broce, Lee and Wiley Families undated (Folder 8)
  - Photographs - School Portraits from Catawba Valley undated (Folder 9)
  - Photographs - Unidentified Portraits undated (Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Buck Family undated (Folder 11)
  - Craig County Families - Brickey, Abbott, Layman, Crawford, Sarver, Lee, Arnn And Reynolds undated (Folder 12)
  - Records - Catawba Area of Roanoke County 1920 (Folder 13)